(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-26T16:20:01.408773",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
開演まで しばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ATTENTION ご来場のお客様へ
[Notice to Attendees]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
ATTENTION 演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
ATTENTION: Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
アニメにハマって 歌いたくなっちゃった！
Got hooked on anime and wanted to sing!
推しのシーン見ながら カラオケ歌えるなんて…
Being able to sing karaoke while watching my favorite scenes...
尊すぎてつらいっ！
It's too precious and overwhelming!
歌いたい曲見つけよう！
Let's find the song you want to sing!
歌い倒さんど！
Sing your heart out!
本日が…
Today is...
皆様、ホロライブ 2nd Fes. Beyond the Stage ファーストミッションにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you all so much for attending Hololive 2nd Fes. Beyond the Stage First Mission!
飲食場外、
Outside the dining area,
グッズ物販所へ
to the merchandise booth...
ホロックスのグッズ売場へどうぞ！
Please head to the HoloroX merchandise booth!
みなさん、まったー！
Everyone, wait—!
ホロックスの女幹部、高嶺ルイとおまします！
I am Takane Lui, female executive of HoloroX!
みんな、参上や！
Everyone, we have arrived!
ホロックスの、の……、あくいんこよりだよー！
HoloroX's se... secret agent Hakui Koyori here!
沙花叉さんは……、か、株……？
Sakamata-san is... st... stock...?
おお、よくできたわ！ホロックスの用心棒、一命を賭して守り抜く風でござる！
Oh, well done! As HoloroX's bodyguard, I shall protect you with my life!
最後までライブを楽しみにしていただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure you fully enjoy the live concert until the end, we have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機器の使用は固くお断りいたします。
Photography, audio recording, and video recording equipment are strictly prohibited during the performance.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
Should you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and notify nearby staff immediately.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、大きく飛び跳ねる、ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他のみんなの迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
Mosh pits, diving, excessive jumping, or throwing objects onto the stage are strictly prohibited as they disturb others and disrupt the show.
また、3階と4階の最前列席は危険防止のため立ち入り禁止です。
Also, standing in the front row seats of the 3rd and 4th floors is prohibited for safety reasons.
ルールを守って盛り上がってくださいね！お守りいただけない場合、ご退場いただく可能性がございます。
Please follow the rules and enjoy yourselves! Failure to comply may result in removal from the venue.
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に這い、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
Additionally, streaming and photography cameras will be operating in the venue during this performance, and audience members may be captured.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please note that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「#SSホロックス世界リペイント計画」です！
Also, the official live hashtag is "#SSHoloroXWorldRepaintPlan"!
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください！
Please use the hashtag to hype up the event!
それでは、開演までもう少しです！みんなで一緒に盛り上がるでござる！
Now, the curtain rises soon! Let's get hyped together, de gozaru!
みんな……、しずかに……、しずかに……。
Everyone... quietly... quietly...
好き嫌い言わずに ちゃんと食べてね
Without being picky, eat it all properly.
人参だって ピーマンだって
Even carrots, even green peppers!
モラトリアム エデンの星を滑る者
Moratorium, slider of Eden's stars,
秘密結社ホロックス！
Secret Society holoX!
常夜リペイント！
Tokoyami Repaint!
キミは熟した？
Are you ripe yet?
宵闇より現れしエージェントよ
Agents emerging from the twilight,
準備はいいかい？
Are you ready?
行くぞ！
Let's go!
Are you ready?
ラパパ…
La-pa-pa...
夜が深まる ほらDarkness
As night deepens, behold, Darkness,
脳裏にでっかいウェポンで隠す
concealing a giant weapon in your mind.
何したってYay! エゴイスティックに
No matter what, Yay! Egotistically,
脳内に眠るサムライが
the samurai sleeping in your mind
読みきれないけど
can't be read, but
フルベットでしょ 借金借金
it's all-in, debt after debt,
絶望ゲッ! 小さく赤字じゃ金欠金欠
despair get! In the red and broke,
悪の手の平
in the palm of evil,
踊りてくなル おバカにも気づけばノリノリです
wanting to dance, you realize you're hyped up.
どうしようもない どうしようもない
Helpless, helpless,
宇宙でメイク?
making up in space?
なんかしょうがない
can't be helped, though,
もう全部塗り替えろよ
repaint everything right now!
XとXとXとXが交差する真ん中で
right in the middle where X, X, X, and X cross.
XとXとXと業界はもう始まってるじゃん
The industry with X, X, X has already begun!
Whoo... 飛びな飛びな 闇が呼ぶ方へ
Whoo... Fly, fly towards where the darkness calls,
暗黒の雲 Xです
cloud of darkness, it's X.
混沌としたこの世界を 我らホロックス色に塗り替えるのだ！
Let's repaint this chaotic world in our holoX colors!
みなのもの、かかる！
Everyone, attack!
Yes! My Dark!
アブソリュート ダークネス インフィニティ
Absolute Darkness Infinity!
エデンの星は 我が掌に
Eden's stars are in my palm.
ラパパ… 限界ミリ秒
La-pa-pa... limit milliseconds.
風穴開けたんだ 支配は始まった
We opened a breach, domination has begun.
息はもう掛けたの 罰ゾーンの 近くないはずよ
I've already breathed on it, shouldn't be near the penalty zone.
抑えきれない 自力制御不能のパワー
An uncontrollable, self-powered force
捕まえてみなよ 影かたちもないマイハダ
try to catch it, with no shadow or form.
半死半生 蘇生はのの心に従って
Half-dead, half-alive, resurrection follows the heart.
抽選見せてよ 今こそ baby don't rely down
Show the lottery, now baby don't rely down.
絡みキリミ クセになりそうになるでしょ
Entangling sashimi, likely becoming a habit.
Yes! スプレン カジュアレスショウ
Yes! Splendid casual show.
革命的存在をいつか スプレシュー 大感情 吹きさして
Someday blowing through a revolutionary existence with great emotion.
まがほかい
Magahokai
お前もホロカの一員となるのだ
You too shall become a member of Holoca!
So lonely
To be my life
Do you remember me?
まがまが とめが
Magamaga, tomeda,
ああ 時は赤々
ah, times are glowing red
まっかっかだ まったくただ
completely fiery, totally just
それはウィンク ウィンク
It's a wink, a wink,
引く手もずっと赤々
drawing red crowds constantly
エンプレスアイ風の目 ウィンク
Empress iPhone's eye, wink
ちょっと お前がたい 眼に入れたくないくらい
Wanting you so much I wouldn't put you in my eye
ならはららくちましに スイートジャスティス
Narahararakuchimashini, sweet justice
憎しみのは とくにすたれ
The leaf of hatred, especially outdated
こわがっての ふーん ああそう
Being scared? Huh, is that so?
Don't let me down
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet
アンセインじゃいけない 健全じゃいけない
Insane won't do, wholesome won't do either
それがなんだ プランティだね
What is that? It's plenty, right?
眼には目を
An eye for an eye
ウィンク
Wink
知らぬ間 見聞き
Unknowingly seeing and hearing,
まるきり君え ウィンク 知らぬ間やまかっかだ
completely you. Wink, unknowingly fiery
oh I I I I want you let by your side
Oh I I I I want you right by your side
さあ目に物を見せる my I I
Now I'll show you what I'm made of, my I I
目を つむる半分めがうウィンク
Closing eyes halfway, a mega wink
まがお まがお まがお ほらグラ まったくまに
Magao, magao, magao, look at the city, totally in time
I kill you
ほら凛々しい まっぽん
Hey, dignified Mappon!
これで君も
With this, you too
ほら 凛々しめカメラ！
Hey, a dignified camera!
みんなの脳みさに お注射しちゃうぞ
I'm gonna give everyone's brain an injection!
チキンタタン チキンタタン
Chicken tatan, chicken tatan
いっしょにワクワク チキンタタン
Together, excited, chicken tatan
チキンタタン チキンタタン チキンタタン
Chicken tatan, chicken tatan, chicken tatan
研究 研究 研究 研究しょしょちゅう
Research, research, research, research all the time
呼ばれて飛び出て ポンピコポンポン
Called upon, jumping out, pon-piko pon-pon
化粧 化粧 化粧 単純 アテンションプリーズ
Makeup, makeup, makeup, simple attention please
舐めてたらやけろしちゃうよ
If you underestimate me, you'll get burned!
迷ったダメダメ 迷ったたくさんイエス
Lost? No no, lost, a lot of yes!
迷宮呪文 まよまよチュンチュン
Labyrinth spell, mayo-mayo chun-chun
今夜もデザイン アット 今夜もハッピー 今夜に恋したんで恋行方
Tonight's design, tonight's happy too, in love tonight, love's whereabouts
サイレン サイレン 三千世界 Sick sick sick ドキドキ耐久戦
Siren, siren, three thousand worlds, sick sick sick, pounding endurance battle
僕らの天才 心がホニー
Our genius heart is honey
天才 天才 天才 どんでもなくえんどん
Genius, genius, genius, incredibly endless
抱きしめちゃってオッケー ホームシックサイン ドン
Hug me is okay, home-sick sign, boom!
最高 最高 最高 どんでもなく優勝
The best, the best, the best, unbelievably triumphant
ぶっ飛ぶ脳汁 シュワシュワサバリング オープンショー
Blowing brain juice, fizzy sabering, open show!
タタタっとワンパターンのハートをポスッとピポパン
Tatata-to, one-pattern heart, pos-to pipopan
間違えせんとことんの 角を曲げ散らかすぞ
Turning corners of endless mistakes
異様異様 脳みそつむる半分めがうウィンク
Strange strange, brain-closing half mega-wink
チキンタタン チキンタタン
Chicken tatan, chicken tatan
チキンタタン チキンタタン チキンタタン
Chicken tatan, chicken tatan, chicken tatan
さあさあ もっと声出せるよね
Come on, you can raise your voices more, right?
じゃあ いっしょに チキンタタンって叫ぶよ
Then together, let's shout "Chicken tatan!"
せーの
Ready, go!
チキンタタン
Chicken tatan!
心寄せ微か歌う
I gently gather my heart and faintly sing
花の根になりたい
Wanting to become the roots of flowers
色づくその前より
Before they start to color
ちゃんと地に立ちたい
I want to stand firmly on the ground
唇を芽吹かせる
Making my lips sprout buds
遣らずの雨が降ろうと
Even if an uncharitable rain falls
惰性に時を喋ることなく
Without wasting time on inertia
頼みの声を灯せば
If I light a voice of reliance
油煙も在りし日の
Even soot and oil from days gone by
記憶にできるから
Can become memories
涙雲に一筋の風が吹く
A single streak of wind blows through the tears of clouds
桜は散らなければ愛されないと
That cherry blossoms aren't loved unless they fall
光らぬ羽虫に夏なしと
That dull insects have no summer
比べられようが
However they may be compared
竹を打ち割るほどに
Enough to split bamboo
身を削るほどに梓を打つ
Enough to whittle my body and strike the bow
有り明けの先で
Beyond the dawn
心寄せ微か歌う
I gently gather my heart and faintly sing
常しえに遥か忍ぶ
Enduring far away into eternity
金色の髪が靡く
Golden hair flutters in the wind
頑丈で頑固な心臓でも
Even with a sturdy and stubborn heart
湧き溶めす志向に
Melted into the ambition
心寄せ微か歌う
I gently gather my heart and faintly sing
常しえに遥か忍ぶ
Enduring far away into eternity
一雫の水のように
Like a single drop of clear water
金色の髪が靡く
Golden hair flutters in the wind
どうしようもないどうしようもないほどに
Feeling so helpless, so utterly helpless
満たしてくネームレス
Fulfilling my nameless self
場所がないもう全部塗り替えよう
There's no place, let's repaint everything
晦ませよ高めくせよ
Conceal it, make your heart beat higher
エクストリームエクストリーム交差する真ん中で
Right in the middle where extremes intersect
ネクストネクストネクスト世界はもう始まってるじゃん
Next, next, next, the world has already begun!
コピナコンピナ生まれ変わりドリーム
Copy and paste, reborn dream
笑うのはホロクステ
Laughing is HoloX
ラパパ ラパパ ラパパ パラパ
Ra pa pa, ra pa pa, ra pa pa, parapa
ホロクステのライブが始まるぞ
HoloX's live concert is starting!
始まるぞ
It's starting!
こんにちわ こんにちわ
Hello! Hello!
こんにちは
Hello!
全然一癖のない身のこなしですね
Your movements have absolutely no quirks at all!
さあ！狂気の歌劇の始まりだ！
Now! The madness opera begins!
貴様ら！高めくせよ
You scoundrels! Make your hearts beat!
我が輩の名前はラプラスダークネスだ
My name is La+ Darknesss!
はい！皆さんまたー
Yes! Everyone, see you again—!
新しいのよ。どう？披露目それね
Something new. How is it? The debut, right?
ホロクステのお腹幹部
HoloX's upper management
高嶺ルイと申します
I am Takane Lui!
ちょっと新しいのいきますよ
I'll do a slightly new one!
あの子より！その子より！
More than that girl! More than that girl!
より！
More!
イケてるじゃんすたーい
Looking so cool, style!
ありがとう！初めてやりました
Thank you! I did it for the first time!
ホロクステの頭脳！白衣こよりだよ
HoloX's brain! Hakui Koyori here!
お前たち！分かってるよね？
You guys! You know what's up, right?
ごぜるさんは
Kazama-san is...
かわいい
Cute!
おろっくす？可愛い！
HoloX? Cute!
ごぜるさんは！ かわいい！
Kazama-san is! Cute!
ホロクステのイケメンちゅうちゅおかっこいいおじも風間の風色羽だぜ
HoloX's handsome, cool, and charming Kazama Iroha!
やっとね、ついにこの日が来てしまった
Finally, this day has come.
は、始まっちゃった！
It- it's starting!
実感なかった！
It didn't feel real!
よかったね
Glad it finally came.
危ない危ない
That was close, close.
最初のメドレー、すごくあったでしょ？
The first medley was amazing, right?
みんなこんな風に混ざってソロ狂って、予想できてたー！？
Did you expect everyone to mix and go wild on solos like this?!
ペンライト点けて。
Turn on your penlights.
だよね？だよね？
Right? Right?
いやそうよ。
Yeah, exactly.
もう、そう、最初からクライマックス、それぐらいの盛り上がりではあって。
It was like a climax right from the start, with that much hype.
始まったばっかだけどね。
Even though it just started.
始まったばっかといえばさ、もう、みんなあの、自己紹介の時に、実はずっとみんなもうちょっとうるっときてて。
Speaking of just starting, during self-introductions, we were actually getting a bit teary-eyed.
え？やめて、その話は！
Eh? Stop, don't talk about that!
その話はもう、ガクトやろ！
Let's drop that topic!
この時点でのルイさんは、いや、そう、1番早かったのはルイから。
At that point, Lui-san... well, Lui was the fastest.
いつも、いつもルイからだから。
It's always from Lui.
違うの？ルイさん。違うの？
Is it different, Lui-san? Different?
か、花粉症？
H- Hay fever?
任せなよ！いや、任せないでしょ。
Leave it to me! No, we can't leave it to you.
や、や、や。
N- N- No.
いいじゃん、素直にメンバー大好きって書いてあって。
It's fine, it shows how much you love the members.
泣き出しそう。
I'm about to cry.
俺も素敵。
Me too, wonderful.
よかったよ。泣き出して。
It was good. Starting to cry.
それをさ、みんなずっといじってたのに、あの、ここ来てみんなの笑顔を見たらさ、ちょっとみんな、
Even though everyone kept teasing you, when we came here and saw everyone's smiles...
いや、そう、うるっときて。
Yeah, we got a bit teary.
なんか始まる前はさ、みんななんかもうこんなんで待ってた。
Before it started, everyone was waiting like this.
自己紹介始まった瞬間、うるってみたいな。
The moment self-introductions started, we went "uh..." like that.
めっちゃ笑顔でうるってなって、みんなのね、なんか、声とか、なんか音とかすごくって、みんな泣いてた。
With huge smiles, everyone's voices and sounds were so amazing, everyone was crying.
そう、で、うるってきて、でも、やんなきゃって、やったんだよね？
That's right, we got teary, but we thought "we have to do it," and did it, right?
いや、やらないといけないよね？うん。
Yeah, we have to do it, right? Yeah.
もう今日はかまさないといけないよね？
Today we've gotta rock it, right?
でもお1曲目はかませたんじゃないか？かませてた！
But didn't we rock the first song? We rocked it!
かませてたー！
We rocked it!
でもさ、最初のさ、曲のメドレーのさ、タイトル言ってやってよ。
But hey, say the title of the first song medley and do it!
ちょっと待って、これ読めるの？
Wait, can I read this?
めっちゃかっこよく言えるよ。
You can say it super coolly.
じゃあラプ、代表して、お願いします。みんな、まあ、教育でさ、みんな知ってるよね？
Then Lapu, on behalf of everyone, please. Everyone, you all know it from education, right?
そうだよね、素晴らしい。今日のための特別タイトル、アッカラン。
That's right, wonderful. The special title for today, Akkaran.
そうなのよ。そう、ケミな。
That's right. Kemi-na.
発見んだから。
Because I discovered it.
行くぜ！やります。
Let's go! We'll do it.
今日はXです。エクステンドリミックス、みんなの必殺技を詰め込んでみましたバージョン！
Today is X. Extended Remix, crammed with everyone's special moves!
なんか最後ちょっと、そのまんまなんでよ。無理やりじゃない？
It's just like that at the end. Isn't it forced?
かっけえ！
So cool!
かっこよかったぜ！決まったぜ！って。サイシング組も盛り上がってますか？
So cool! Nailed it! Are the sizing team getting hyped too?
サイシング組も盛り上がってるよー！盛り上がってるぜー！
The sizing team is getting hyped too! Getting hyped!
コメントも見えてるからね。
We can see the comments too, you know.
コメントも「イエイ、ウォーー！」しか言ってない。
The comments are only saying "Yay, woohoo!"
かっけえ、お、タイトル長いて言われてる！
So cool, oh, they're saying the title is long!
いやどう考えても、本人の名前より短いじゃん！
No matter how you think about it, it's shorter than their actual name!
確かに！そう！本名より短いよ。
True! That's right! It's shorter than their real name.
そういえば、もうみんな、配信前だから気づいたと思うけど。
Come to think of it, everyone probably noticed before the stream.
DJ！
DJ!
DJ！最高！最高だよ！
DJ! The best! Absolutely the best!
怖くないよにね。
Not scary at all.
そう、本当だよ。
Yeah, really.
ちょっと怖いよ。
A bit scary though.
怖いよ絶対。あそこ超たけえぜ。
Definitely scary. That place is super high.
いうわけで、
So,
ここから先は本当の任務に入っていくぞ！
from here on, we're entering the real mission!
行くぞ！始まったぞ！
Let's go! It has begun!
なんですが、
But,
ここで、嫌だ！俺は聞かないぞ！話。
right here... No! I'm not listening! Stories.
まさか、ありません。
No way, there isn't.
ちょっと私から言うのもあれなんだけど、これ。おいおいおい！
It's a bit awkward for me to say this, but... Hey hey hey!
その口を借りるな！
Don't use those words!
はい、ではちょっと大事なお知らせです。
Okay, now for a very important announcement.
YouTube、TikTokライブでご覧になっている方、無料チラ見せはここまでとなります！
For those watching on YouTube and TikTok Live, the free preview ends here!
さあ！
Now!
関係ないのに、えーって言ってくれてる。
Even though it's unrelated, they're going "Ehh!"
未練のね。
Such attachment.
関係ない。
Unrelated.
すみません。
Sorry.
ですが、この後もあんなパフォーマンスや、ゴージャスな楽曲など、今からでも間に合いますので、このへん概要欄からこのへん配信チケットを購入してください！ここ！ここ！ここ！役割分担で。
However, you can still make it in time for performances and gorgeous songs, so get tickets from the description!
お前ら、絶対買えよな！肩落とした、買った音、あれはやばいよ。
You guys, definitely buy it! Dropping shoulders, buying sound, that's crazy.
そして、このライブの感想などはですね、ハッシュタグSSホロックス世界リペイント計画でポストしてくださいね！お願いします！
And for your thoughts on this live, please post them with the hashtag #SSHoloxWorldRepaintPlan!
お願いします！お願いします！
Please! Please!
そしてそして、配信組はいっぱいスクショ撮ってアップしてね！
And also, streaming viewers, take lots of screenshots and upload them!
お願いしまーす！
Please!
盛り上げてね！じゃあかっちゃん！
Get hyped! Now, Katchan!
ってことで、
So,
じゃあここからね、さっき言ってた通り、
as we talked about earlier,
本当のミッション始まりますわね！
the real mission is about to begin!
はい！
Yeah!
おーい！
Hey!
まだ声出せるよなー！
You can still make some noise, right?!
おー！いいねー！
Whoa! That's awesome!
最高です！
This is the best!
ここにいる全員、そして配信の民！
Everyone here, and everyone watching the stream!
覚悟はいいか！
Are you ready?!
ファーストミッション！
First Mission!
ここからが本番だー！
This is where the real show begins!
それでは、任務続行！
Now then, mission proceed!
無料パートは終了いたしました！ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.